all right everybody it's early morning
and it's like 5:00
a.m. and I've been going through the
comments and rdit and we've got like
2200 views on my Neo video and I'm
absolutely
terrified that it's going to be taken
the wrong way and sure enough there's
been out of all the comments they've
almost all been supportive my most the
most hilarious comment was one that was
like it was it was like a seven line
comment with
one uh with somebody saying I watched
this for one minute and then they
proceeded to ask questions that were
answered in the first 5 minutes that
they would have gotten answers to had
they watched the video for five minutes
it's a long video I don't do short
videos usually I mean I try but the
question really before me is is is one
that I'm very seriously contemplating
and I want your feedback on it so I'm
going to post this video to Reddit so we
can have a discussion thread and um I
very seriously want your answers here
should you keep
your noted mistakes available
online that's the
question there's stuff in my Z casting
that I no longer agree with at all that
video that I did was me deleting stuff
from my knowledge
base with ranty stuff that I didn't
believe in anymore and and the nature of
Isle casting is you're supposed to be
able to to take those things out of
there and I mean if you guys know about
my zcast then we can go look it up see
I'm going to take this down by the way
this is this is the Tamer of the
articles but if you go to my if you go
to github.com
uh or sorry z.
GitHub uh did I get that right what is
it rwx rob. github.io is that I think so
here's my index is that I'll cast in
right and the idea of this and this is
this has got you know positive things
about NE so every time something gets
updated this gets updated right and I'm
not put this I'm not pushing this that's
not what this video is about I hate it
when people people keep doing this like
I'm pretty sure this guy's just trying
to pump his views I'm like no I'm not
like why would you spend so much time on
this I said I answered that I described
it in the video I deal with people who
are learning all the time I have my
whole life I started my own business on
it the reason I spend time on on these
videos is to help people learn and know
where to go that's the only reason I'm
doing it I don't give a yeah sure
the money pays for my starlink so I can
IRL stream but anybody that knows me at
all knows that stop stop saying
like that okay anyway so and yeah that's
yet another disconnected diet tribe to
quote somebody exactly you know people
are like how dare you read your comments
you know you're going to you're just
going to beat yourself up reading the
comments well I'm asking you to make
more comments beating me up hopefully
you'll be kind about it but the question
is very
simple should you leave up your content
that you no longer agree with what do
you think that's it it that's still
that's the Crux of this video that's the
Crux of this video if you don't see
anything else now you can stop you can
make a
comment you know I'm going to tell you
what I think and where I'm my current
position is but why I'm rethinking it
um
uh I think
that it's
impossible to get people in 2024
to take the
time to read enough or to watch it they
they won't even watch like they won't
even watch more than a minute a
video people have Trolling Videos where
the actual video is containing in the
last five minutes because they know
people won't watch
it given
this
context the real question is do we care
about those people and the answer is yes
I actually do
you know why because those are the
people that I want to get to the people
who spend one
minute on a 60-minute explanation video
where all the best part is at the end
and they didn't even go to the end to
see
it those people are the
most I can I I could you know say bad
things about them or whatever we could
all make fun of them or we could try to
help
them and I deal with these people all
the time I've been dealing with people
like this for more than a decade
professionally
I have not I'm not talking about at work
I'm talking about helping people to
learn most of them are younger they're
in the 18 18 age and it is a disease
friends it is a
disease this dopamine addicted I have to
get all my answers in one minute answer
me really right away or I'm going to
walk away and I'm going to Flame
you that
behavior comes from a disease and the
disease is worse than Co the disease is
the lack of a ability to create any
autodidactic research at all and you see
it at odds with people there's other
comments in the Reddit and other people
there's people who have figured this out
and they they behave like self-taught
people on a Linux news group or in IRC
chat and then you have the people that
ask the questions there's people who
have made sites called let me Google
that for you and you put those two
groups of people together and you get
nothing but toxic you get nothing but
toxic you get the people who have spent
the time they know how to answer their
own questions
and they think the people that put one
minute in and ask questions are absolute
morons and they go off on them and the
and the dynamic between those two is
very toxic and
unhealthy and I'm just describing the
climate because that's the climate we're
in so what do we want to do about it
right what do we want to do about it do
we want to just accept it the way it is
and cater to the people who have already
become enlightened and know how to
figure out how to answer their own
questions or do we do we want to roast
everybody like I did for the first year
on Twitch some of you might remember
this but for the first year on Twitch if
someone came into my and this was on
purpose by the way it was a technique I
used to use uh in my school as well as
here and and it's
questionable but it's not unusual right
they would come people would ask
questions they can answer on their and I
would roast them I would roast them but
it was a it was a roast of Love honestly
honest to God it was a roast of love
because I was like I don't know you tell
me like like you know why are you it it
did come off kind of like why are you
wasting my time and one time one time
this is a direct quote I had a guy come
in some of you might actually remember
this I had a guy come into my chat I
assume it was a guy I don't know and
everybody assumes this a guy I'm sure
I'm going to get comments on that too um
I had somebody come in my chat and they
said they asked me a question and
uh they said it was a chat about or
something and I said some SN remark like
it's in the
title and and they shot back and they
said you know you could have told me
that instead of making fun of me it
would have taken you less
time how do you feel about
that and then the next comment they said
was and they weren't wrong you're just a
big as as people say
the ironic thing is is if they had been
paying me to come to my school it would
have done the same
thing because because it's a disease
it's a disease and and this is going to
come I'm going to get a comment saying
you're saying people that ask questions
are disease that's not what I'm saying
what I'm saying is that
people somehow I don't know how but a
large percentage of people in the
world have not learned the most
important skill the absolute most
important skill not just in technology
but in life and I'm not talking about
loving others I'm talking about getting
your own answers to
questions becoming an autodidact and if
you go to skills. this is this is the
site sell free but you know start your
Tech Career there's an unusually large
amount of
content that talks about knowing it's
never T thinking like a hacker right and
you know people most of most of these
people these people that come there
thank you for the fall the people the
people
who the people who
cha at this stuff it's really sad
because this is one of the things that I
cannot it's very hard for me to help
people online that's why I'm making a
video here with this problem because I
can't I can't you know these days you
can't even put your arm around somebody
right you can't you can't even touch
them but if I'm in person with somebody
like I used to be in my own brick and
morar and it's we're having you know
we're having game nights and we're
having fun together and we have a
relationship that's the point I'm trying
to make right
and and and then when they ask me a
question they can answer on their own I
can poke them I can jab them I can say
look you
know why are you being so intellectually
lazy that's my term for
it you know and the the problem with
this is that the disease is intellectual
laziness it's this this lack of desire
to even lift the finger to understand
the tick the the topic or to do your own
research or to sit through somebody's
explan you know winding in uh to put up
with their rhetorical style and actually
listen and care about what they say
people do not want to spend the time
listening to each other watching each
other's videos
writing a a you know a good response
instead of a mean one the disease the
YouTube you know problem is is not that
people you know are trolls and they want
to create fights it's because they're
just
lazy people are
lazy and you know I I'm lazy but I hope
it's in a good way you know I but the
the intellectual laziness is the thing I
got very little patience for but
I I want to help people with it so
why did I talk about all of that there's
at least one commenter is's going to say
oh my God he's going off on all this
philosophical he's not staying with
the question in the middle of the title
and I am but it's for a
purpose that is the environment we live
in so if I consider that we live in a a
time where people have are full of
diseased brains that refuse to read
further so you know in a very specific
sense were're talking about people that
would read one of my zle castings that
was written a long time ago and they
would go oh my God this guyy is an
they make their conclusion right
there and they've never you know they
never care to act if I've changed my
mind and I've done this I've done this
and I talked about that in that video I
talked about it in the video I assumed
negative intent when they ripped out
smile and in fact they probably just
didn't get to it because they weren't
done with L yet I mean they weren't done
with Neo yet so I've done it I've
assumed the thing I've I have not spent
enough time
I have borrowed my wife's voting roster
for because I don't have time to read
all the issues on everything and I know
I trust her and she's done it I am just
as subjected to this problem as anyone
and knowing that then I'm going to have
to ask myself a very very very honest
question I have to ask myself hey KRA
how you doing you have to ask yourself a
very honest
question should I make my thoughts
public at all
and I have taken down my
zcon at least five times and then made
it made it private and then made it
public and made it private and then made
it public and made it private and made
it public every time I take it down the
bulk of my community is like oh my God
please put it back I love searching it
it's got so many answers for things that
I
need and AIP I'm with you selective
thoughts to the public is a good
idea that's what people generally do
with
blogs uh they also do that in UCP news
groups which cannot be deleted by the
way once that's why those Linux news
groups are so interesting because you
can't take back something you've said
you can't delete it you can't go on
Reddit and edit your post and make it
something different you can't take your
zle casting down you can't delete a post
it's there forever right and the
argument that they use is that you know
we you need to think about what you're
going to write before write it because
it's going to be permanent everything
you say is
permanent
so the the concept of a zettle Casten a
public zle Casten is fundamentally at at
odds with that if you agree with that
having a public slecting is
fundamentally uh
against the idea of being really careful
what you say because it's going to be
out there forever
now the reason I did it and I've written
about this a lot but the reason I did it
is because I wanted people to see my
thought process happening in real time
the downside of that is that there is
like all kinds of f bombs and in
there because I wrote it in the moment I
make videos in the
moment and people tell me all the time
they they're here for that they want to
hear the authentic real responses they
don't want some contrived can response
they want the authentic reaction the
recent reaction videos are so popular on
YouTube people want the initial reaction
they want to see what your initial
reaction is they want to see what you
really think they don't want you to to
to back off of it and have some nice
happy political response that takes you
you know a full day to edit they want to
know you as a human being they want to
see that but the problem is that that
that that you either have to delete the
video is which I did and this is kind of
partially me explaining that I deleted I
made a I made a an Angry Angry Angry
neoen Video two weeks
ago I mean it was angry it was super
angry and I was wrong I was so wrong in
that video that video was so wrong if
you got a chance to see that
video the video will exist for another
seven days if you there if you still
want to see it you can go find it
there's a VOD of me making that video
but I I just I'm telling you I don't I
deleted it on purpose so communication
is 90% nonverbal that's one reason
people problems happen yeah
absolutely so the point I'm trying to
make here
is I
think I the point I'm trying to make is
I actually don't know I don't know I'm
asking you why am I still up because I
just woke up I slept for 7 hours I went
to bed at
9:00 I went to bed at 9:00 p.m. tonight
so you
know I think I know the answer and for
those of you who come to the end of the
video this is going to be my answer for
now the answer for now
is I will continue to make to write
content and to make
videos based on
what I currently feel and the live
reaction I've had to
something and but I'm going to reserve
the
right to delete content that I no longer
agree
with but I won't have the time to delete
there's I have over what 12,200
videos I have 1200 videos I am not going
to go watch every one of my video and
delete it to see if I still agree with
it or
not should I do that probably I probably
should do that I don't have that kind of
time and at least one person out there
just thought well then you shouldn't
make videos and they're right they are
they're absolutely right I shouldn't be
making videos if I don't have the time
to be responsible about the content of
my videos and actually edit them and go
back and take them down maybe I
shouldn't be making
videos maybe I have no business being
here
you know and and and that is the real
thought that's going through my head
right now and it's not just my thought
that's going through my head there was
another there was a YouTuber there was a
YouTuber who did terminal command line
skills and he had about 70 or 80
fantastic videos about the terminal and
he overnight deleted them all he was
gone like in an instant he was gone and
he he made one last video you going to
remember him he made a video at the very
end and he said good night go to sleep
alaka alaka is
drunk we'll see you tomorrow
buddy and
uh and
uh you know I I was so sad the last
video they made was why they were
getting off
YouTube and they said they were done
with this they were tired of it all
the comments and everything so they had
let the the comments and everything they
had produced amazing videos about how to
use a terminal
and they deleted all of them because of
the YouTube drama over it and they were
like I'm not going to do this anymore
so if people canot understand a Blog
diary not ready to watch YouTube is like
a character to M as a person and I think
I like what you're saying having strong
opinions that you change later mind is
not irresponsible though I agree the
question though manur it is do we want
people to see that process and let me
give you a very specific case I deleted
I deleted those zcast and entries that
contained absolute just full of anger
and passion and stuff and and the main
reason I deleted him is because there
are certain points that part of some it
where it was downright you know
attacking another human and I have tons
of that in my subtle cast and
still if you go back and watch my early
YouTube
videos um there are videos of me
being like lennus tor balds
and actually one of the best parts about
where we're at today I mean I I want to
say that the prim ofin and I have a
pretty good relationship now and I think
that that's for two reasons one I've
grown as a human being and two he's
grown to understand where I was
raised and he spent a lot of time
reading Unix reading Unix mailing lists
and I think the prag when you know when
when we had our drama four years ago I
think it was a fundamental
misunderstanding of where we were coming
from I was coming
from the Linux community and if you if
you want if you and and so calling
someone a is like nothing
absolutely nothing in that Community you
can prime just made a video recently
going through that video actually
there's a little bit of it in the in
it's called vi video I made and he was
reading through the Unix mailing list
and he's trying to Grapple with just how
toxic that Community is and you can tell
that he has come to an understanding of
what it means to be a technologist in
that community in that community and
that's the community I come
from so when I get on YouTube and I call
somebody a or I say you're an
idiot for using yam or something stupid
like that I've never never had the same
level of toxicity and hate associated
with it that that that someone would
attribute to it just who just doesn't
know because that's how we talk to each
other in that community and if you don't
believe me they're still talking to each
other that way in that Community it's
not healthy it's not good they shouldn't
be doing it they should grow out of it I
believe I have grown out of it people
are way too soft people say that they're
way too soft and we need to be tough on
each other that is that's how I am okay
that's how I was raised we we like beat
each other up and then I buy you a beer
that's how I was raised is it right no
it's literally an informal Pals you know
so talk or therapy
then uh not trying to be mean here I
don't know if it feels normal I I agree
Tor wals checked himself into Tor wals
Ln Tor wals checked himself into aner
training but it's clearly hasn't done
anything you should see go read the
comments he just made to the persons
from the r list he's He's
personally attacking him at a level that
is like not even close to him call he's
called people back bursts and ask how
they can feed themselves because they're
so stupid in his own community and and
Prime made you know Prime once made a
video and it was a video that I
considered to be kind of anti- robob
back in the day you can you have to go
find it it's probably I don't know if
it's there and he was legitimately
worried he was like please please be
careful who your mentors
are and his concern was all he knew of
the community I came from was me he's
like please please don't let you know
but now he's made a video recently
where he's saying you know this is a
part of normal Communications in that
community and he's trying to Grapple
with what is normal mean and but the
point is is that I believe Prime and
people like him have have come a long
way in
understanding not it doesn't excuse it
but in understanding what I have had to
deal with and how we talk to each other
and how we have been raised right it's
not okay to do that that it's not it's
okay we need to change we need to stop
talking to each other like that even if
we're good friends this whole good
nature ribbing that that particularly
men do with each other in my experience
that's just my experience but this whole
you know calling each other dicks and
like punching them and that I never
lik that I never liked that never could
get into it I would always be like the
guy who would punch back and i' overly
punch I punch too hard they be like damn
Rob why are you so mean I'm like well
you know we we're joking around I never
got it I never got
it you know so some people have thicker
s than others the Reddit post went
pretty good actually there's only most
people are reading it reading it well so
the question remains do we delete our
stuff so if you if you didn't watch at
the end of this video I don't I'm not
surprised uh you really dislike the
whole bantering culture thing you know
what's funny I've noticed that people um
good communicators people who are good
communicators they don't like it a lot
of people just don't like it the whole
good nature you know that whole it's if
you want a really solid example of this
look at the
military the the military I I one of the
reasons I started out in Roc and one of
the things I was like I realized really
early on that I could not do was this
good nature bantering that happens in
the
military and but if you want to
understand what I'm talking about and
I'm not saying it's bad the people in
the military will talk about each
other constantly and then they'll die
for each other because they're so
closely bonded it's like it's like the
most you know it it's just it's just
amazing you know it's
like so it's like I don't I don't
understand it and they they have their
you know it's almost like you have to
learn a foreign language it's like when
are your insults not insults you
know
um I mean I I would like to understand
that better but I don't feel like I do
and if you're if you're communicating if
you're unless you're like in
person I really feel like you shouldn't
even attempt that if you're in person
then someone can pick up your non-verbal
cues they can they can see your face and
they can know that you don't really mean
that they're a or or you know
whatever the things that we say to each
other whether it be the Linux Community
or the military
um I think if you're in person you're
communicating that way you can pull off
that sort of double on Tandra stuff
right but you certainly I mean this is
obvious you can't do that in a Reddit
post you can't you can't if you're doing
the live stream if I'm the one who's
talking to you and I you can see me move
my hands and stuff and I call you a
and smile I love you you know I
can like diffuse the thing and you can
at least understand that I'm it is a
double on
Tandra but
there's a lot of that that's that's
happening that's turning into hate and
some people Lally try to troll other
people they think it's hilarious and
that's a totally different scop which
we'll talk about at some other point and
I'm not I'm not against scops for a
purpose if that's you know uh but but
that's not what we're talking about here
that's totally different they're more
self-indulgent selfish yes uh you're 22
most of the time I people
lost yeah well I'm see me be openly
wrong help somebody hope so yes so so
again I'm I'm going to end the video now
but but the um this is I I really I mean
I appreciate the comments but I don't
want this to turn into like a Rob pity
party even though I love U pity party
for what's his
name God I love that I love that
YouTuber he's so amazing I can't
remember I can't remember the name now
but I don't want to turn if you ever see
me start wearing like a clown costume
so anyway um yeah I my conclusion as of
this moment is that I'm going to reserve
the right to take
videos uh or or or blog posters elast
down
and uh but I am not going to take
everything
down and the reason for that's largely
one of practical of
practicality um
I I I think I I feel bad
because I feel like part of me is doing
a
disservice
um you know eliminating all content
where that has you being
disagreeable
is my mind in my to my way of thinking
is a little bit disingenuous because
because if you're if you're curating
your persona to the world as being this
person who knows everything and is never
wrong
I feel like that's that's you're not
you're not helping anybody by doing that
I I think people need to
see you be wrong and I I think of
anything that is needed on YouTube they
need more people to be
real and uh as far as I can tell at
least internally I am trying to be real
sometimes I question whether
subconsciously I'm I am acting apart you
know I I don't know it's a very
complicated thing but but I want to be
authentic I want people to see me make
mistakes I want to see me see me swear
and occasionally cry or or or tape my
nipples when I get
drunk you know
it's that's what I want that's what I
want that's what I want to see more of
so you know the best I can do is is try
to provide what I think other people uh
should do
and you know when I see curated
performances and people there's one
thing where people have fun with it you
know and they dress up like a frog
forever or something and I I get that
that's fun but uh and then there's
there's the whole doctor disrespect
thing you know and uh I I don't know I I
personally the content I want to see is
I want to see more people being real and
and that means being wrong in a real way
anytime that I'm wrong though and it it
involves uh tearing someone else down uh
at a personal level
that's going to be the content that I am
absolutely going to delete not because I
want people to think that I'm this guy
who doesn't ever say horrible things
about other people but because because
it's just wrong for the other person to
have that content up there and I I mean
I re I I immediately
regretted going through some of my zle
castings in that previous video from
this one
because I actually read and I hate I
hate that I can't take a back but I'm
not taking that part back I read some of
the things the strong words that I said
and the the personal attacks uh not by
name but by it was pretty obvious in
that last video and you know if I'm
going to follow through on this idea
then I really should have deleted the
last Neen video I just made right
because that was me reading those things
live and that video is going to be
around a long time people are going to
see me people are going to see
me saying horrible things things
that the
people who they were about may have not
even seen yet and I'm terrified that
they're going to read it and they're
going to watch the video and they're
going to see it I I took it I took it I
thought the reaction the reaction of me
reading reading my old was was
going to be video worthy and I kind of
second guessing that now because because
it contains some absolutely horrible
that I didn't even know I was
capable of writing I mean I knew it but
I didn't think I would have left it up
and I did and I found it real time on
the video and I was reading through it
and I was like oh my God I wish I could
immediately pause this video and just
delete this one I don't want this one to
even be out there so anyway that's all
that's all that's that's that's me coffe
having a coffee talk with you in the
morning it's another hourong video um
but yeah thank you AK for the reminder
so so that's it that's it um so the
conclusion is I'm going to continue to
put stuff up authentic reactions in fact
there's going to be a lot more reactions
I'm going to be making I'm going to be
making genuine reaction videos uh to
other Tech videos and that's not to rip
off their content that's because I need
to make sure people a lot of people are
looking at me to inform or help them
make their own decision about what they
should learn and I owe it to them if if
I'm going to do this I owe it to them to
make some sort of response to the stuff
that's out there there
and I am obviously I'm going to spend
more of my time writing code and and and
putting good things out to the universe
and then you know doing the beginner
boost which starts next week um but a
big p percentage of this content that
I'm going to do is going to be direct
responses uh to things and that are not
all negative of course and and so based
on that um uh this video is relevant
because this is going to this is this if
I make a reaction video and my live
reaction is wrong or mean I'm going to
delete that video I'm going to delete it
I'm just telling you right now and but
but if you want to be around for the
live reaction uh you can do that in fact
that's probably the best way to go about
doing this my live reactions will be on
Twitch and they will fade away after 14
days that used to be 60 days now it's 14
after 14 days my live reactions will
Fade Into The Ether they won't exist
anymore
and the um the moments within them that
are worth pushing to the world uh will
be will be you know those will be kept
if if you know if I feel like they're
they're good enough anyway I am I'm fine
tuning my attitude that's what's up
that's what's happening and and by the
way if you know all you have to do is go
watch a video from me back in 2020 and
you can see it's not just my beard
that's
changed it's it's kind of terrifying
actually having having
your entire personality on display and
watching how I've changed over the years
you know I hope I hope I'm going in the
right direction I really do sometimes I
don't know so anyway that's the end for
this video I'm still going to stream I'm
going to go write some code now but but
I I'm going to go ahead and end the
video and go ahead and publish this
right now